Passionate JavaScript developer with outstanding interpersonal skills, years of sales and management experience and a commitment to life-long learning.

# Evan McKinney-Robinson

**07703 859679** evanmckinney94@gmail.com

**JavaScript Developer** 

**View Portfolio Here** 

## **About Me**

I'm a self-taught front-end developer with a passion for delivering high-quality, user-friendly programmes – as demonstrated in my portfolio. My journey began when I started working with music technology in education and other professional settings. As an engineer and sales rep in this environment, it was crucial to have a solid understanding of the technology involved, and a capacity for problem-solving was integral.

After working with various music software programmes, I began developing my own using Max/MSP. I then started developing other programmes with JavaScript and I was hooked instantly. I loved the scope and depth of the language and the fact there was so much to learn – it also just felt highly gratifying to play around with a programme of my own design! I just couldn't stop playing around with it.

I'm a creative and hard-working individual, as exemplified by my first class degree and top college grades – which earned me a discount at university – so programming feels like the natural next-step in my career. I love the fact that I'll constantly be growing, developing and learning as a programmer – which is one of the primary reasons that attracted me to the field.

I'm looking forward to being part of a vibrant team, as I was in my recent sales executive and management role, selling high-tech, specialist music equipment – and consistently ranking as one of the company's top salesmen and service-providers each month.

Languages

JavaScript, HTML, CSS - view portfolio here

**Experience** 

# JavaScript Developer / Web Developer JULY 2020 - CURRENT

For the past six months, I've been busy studying JavaScript in much greater detail and developing larger projects. My work can be viewed in my portfolio, which features a broad range of

programmes and demonstrates a strong comprehension of JS and the surrounding languages and frameworks. This has included developing websites and web application concepts for a handful of clients with small businesses / enterprises.

My strong work ethic, attention to detail and drive to learn more has brought me to this stage, and moving forward I'm keen to master the languages I already know, whilst moving on to understand server-side concepts and other languages in greater detail – such as Node.JS and React – with the intention of eventually becoming a full-stack web developer.

Additionally, I'm keen to explore Swift and work at developing iOS mobile applications, along with improving my knowledge of graphic design and illustration.

# Other Relevant Experience

#### Bop DJ - Manchester

# Assistant Manager / Sales Executive JUNE 2018 - JULY 2020

After university, I worked in a telesales-centered role, selling state-of-the-art music production and DJ equipment to a broad range of clients – varying from five-figure transactions to smaller sales. A capacity for tech support, problem-solving and the ability to communicate complex technical and creative concepts in simple terms was fundamental to the position.

The role required outstanding interpersonal skills to work with unique clients and a diverse team of staff. As a key member of an industry-leading and ever-expanding company, astute time-management and delegation skills were also essential, in order to deal with the often relentless workload.

During my time here I won many awards for my hard work, consistently hitting bonus targets and winning prizes as a top manager, salesman and service provider.

# fluxmusic.net

#### Editor / Writer / Content Creator AUG 2017 - DEC 2020

Additionally, after graduating, I worked for an <u>online music</u> <u>magazine</u>, record label and event company in my spare time. I initially applied to be a writer, but was offered an editorial position due to my strong application. Along with writing, editing, team-management and organisational skills, this role gave me an insight into the process of managing a website from a

content-creation and design perspective, working with Wordpress and often dealing with small coding bugs in order to get things published on time and to the highest possible standard. It was an amazing experience, which left me hungry to learn more about development.

# **Education**

# **Leeds Beckett University** - 1st Class Degree - (BA) Music Production

**SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017** 

# West Cheshire College – $D^*D^*D$ – (BTEC National Diploma) Music Technology

**SEPTEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2013** 

## References

#### **Conor Moxon**

Company Director, Bop DJ 2 Church Walk Leeds LS2 7EG cmoxon@bopdj.com / info@bopdj.com 07968 445996

## **Tom Bowers**

Course Director & Senior Lecturer, Leeds Beckett University
Leeds Beckett University
Headingley Campus
LS6 3QT
t.bowers@leedsbeckett.ac.uk
0113 81 27424